Woodrow Wilson Collection, 1837-1986 (bulk 1883-1924 ): Preliminary Finding Aid MC168
Public Policy Papers
- Series 10: Papers of Others About Woodrow Wilson, 1837-1986 October 14; 58 boxes; 2 folders
  - Swem, Charles L., 1894-1986 October 14; 24 boxes
    - Woodrow Wilson, 1894-1986 October 14; 20 boxes
      - Printed Matter, 1904-1920; 2 boxes
        - Addresses – Complete cards, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 10)
        - Addresses Incomplete cards, undated; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 11)
        - Congressional reports, 1919-1920; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 1)
        - Documents on American Oriental Relations, 1916; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 2)
        - Federal Trade Commission, 1916 January, 1916 March, 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 3)
        - Fragments – The Story of the Great War; Catholic National Series; Fifth Reader, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 4)
        - House of Representatives – Committee on the Merchant Marine and Fisheries, undated; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 5)
        - House of Representatives Reports, 1917; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 6)
        - Law: Sherman Antitrust –, 1911 July; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 7)
        - Law: State of New Jersey, 1913; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 7)
        - League of Nations, 1919; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 8)
        - Magazine Clippings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 10)
        - Miscellaneous – re World War I, undated; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Papers of Others than Swem, Charles L., 1913-1920; 1 box
      - Newspaper clippings, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 1)
      - Secretaries of State: Bryan, William J., Lansing, Robert, 1915-1916; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 2)
      - Senate-Reports, 1913-1919; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 3)
      - United States Anthracite Coal Commission Report, 1920; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 4)
      - Annual Reports, War Department, –, 1915 July 1; 1916 October 1; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 5)
      - Watson, Sir Charles: "The Next War: Wilsonism and Anti Wilsonism", undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - Boggs, Lucy H., TLS to Bones, Helen Woodrow, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Judge Cohalan re Irish rebellion and support of Germany, 1916 April 17; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 8)
      - Dr. Grayson, telegram (night letter), Knauss, H. E, 1913; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 9)
      - Dr. Grayson, telegram (night letter), McAdoo, W. G., undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 9)
      - Lee, Blair, Memorandum – "Over Centralization Brought on the World War,", 1917 January 3; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 10)
      - McAdoo, William Gibbs, 1916; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 12)
      - Morganthau, Henry, Gallery Proofs Ambassador Morgenthau's Story, undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 13)
      - Prowse, Charles O., TLS to Starling, E. W, 1917 April 24; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 14)
      - Prowse, Charles O., Memorandum –, 1917 April 23; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 14)
      - Ross, E. P. R., Memoranda –, 1917 April 23; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 15)
      - Simms, J. M. and Gwynne, L. H., "Victory and After", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 16)
      - Tumulty, Joseph P., Works, Correspondence, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 17)
      - Wilson, Edith Bolling, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 18)
      - Writings about Wilson, Woodrow (including Wilson, Ellen Axson), undated; 1 folder (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - Swem, Charles L., Personal, 1915-1919; 3 boxes
      - Writings – unpublished MS. Of book on Wilson, Woodrow, and other writings, undated; 1 box
        - Shorthand Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 1)
        - Shorthand Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 2)
        - Shorthand Notes – Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 3)
        - Re Appointments to Office, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 4)
        - Re As Lawyer and First Campaign, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 5)
        - Re Character, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 6)
        - Re Criticism, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 7)
        - Re Early Life, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 8)
        - Re Growth of a President, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 9)
        - Re Humor, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 10)
        - Re Law and Humaneness, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 11)
        - Re League of Nations, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 12)
        - Re Miscellaneous Notes, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 13)
        - Re Mexico, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 14)
        - Re Peace Conference and Going Abroad, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 15)
        - Re Second Campaign, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 16)
        - Re Suffrage and Prohibition, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 17)
        - Re War, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 18)
        - "I want to be a success in life, ..." TMS, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 19)
        - "The Man Who Limped" TMS with shorthand corrections in pencil, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 20)
        - "The man who wrote opportunity knocked once..." TMs with shorthand corrections in pencil, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 21)
        - "The Perfect Crime" TMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 22)
        - "Shorthand Talks" TMss Number 1 "The Importance of the First Principles", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 23)
        - "Shorthand Talks" TMss Number 2 "Shorthand Penmanship", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 23)
        - Story, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 24)
        - "There are two ways to take a trip" TMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 25)
        - "This is the day of the secretary", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 26)
        - "U.S.S.S.", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 27)
        - When the armistice was signed, ... TMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 28)
        - Captain Kidd's Treasure (play) TMs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 29)
        - To Aunt Minnie (poetry) TMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence, 1915-1919; 1 box
        - General A-W, undated; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 1)
        - Swem, Daisy, to Swem, Charles L., ("Snookums"), 1919; undated; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 2)
        - Swem, Charles L., to Swem, Daisy, ("Ooks"), 1915; 1918; 1919; undated; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Diary and Notebooks, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - Documents, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - Photographs, 1919; 2 boxes
        - France, Peace Conference, 1919; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 6)
        - Personal – Photographs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 1)
        - Negatives – Photographs, undated; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Memorabilia, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous Material, undated; 1 box
        - About Swem, Charles, – Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 4)
        - General Miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - Printed Matter, undated; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1914 July 28-1930; 17 boxes
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation: World War I Reports, 1914 July 28-1919; 15 boxes
      - #1, –, 1914 July 28; 1914 December 31; 1 box (Box 90)
      - #2, –, 1915 January 1; 1915 June 30; 1 box (Box 91)
      - #3, –, 1915 July 1; 1915 December 31; 1 box (Box 92)
      - #4, –, 1916 January 1; 1916 June 29; 1 box (Box 93)
      - #5, –, 1916 July 1; 1916 December 31; 1 box (Box 94)
      - #6, –, 1917 January 1; 1917 April 30; 1 box (Box 95)
      - #7, –, 1917 May 1; 1917 September 30; 1 box (Box 96)
      - #8, –, 1917 October 1; 1917 December 31; 1 box (Box 97)
      - #9, –, 1918 January 1; 1918 April 30; 1 box (Box 98)
      - #10, –, 1918 May 1; 1918 July 31; 1 box (Box 99)
      - #11, –, 1918 August 1; 1918 September 30; 1 box (Box 100)
      - #12, –, 1918 October 1; 1918 December 31; 1 box (Box 101)
      - #13, –, 1919 January 1; 1919 March 31; 1 box (Box 102)
      - #14, –, 1919 April 1; 1919 June 30; 1 box (Box 103)
      - #15, –, 1919 July 1; 1919 December 31; 1 box (Box 104)
    - Baker, Lawrence, Political Campaign Material Scrapbook, dates not examined; 13 folders (Box 105, Folder 1-13)
    - Pfeiffer, Timothy, Scrapbook, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 14)
      (News Clippings, Magazines, Pamphlets, etc.)
    - Unidentified member of the press, undated; 1 box
      - Scrapbooks, undated; 2 folders (Box 106, Folder 1-2)
        (News Clippings, Typed Notes, Unidentified)
    - Oversized Scrapbooks, 1929-1930; 1 box
      (See Oversized, Box 114-116)
      - Halleran, W. J., Scrapbook, Newspaper Articles, undated; 1 box (Box 106)
      - Halleran, W. J., Scrapbook, Newspaper Articles, 1929-1930; 1 box (Box 106)
      - Halleran, W. J., Scrapbook, Newspaper Articles, undated; 1 box (Box 106)
- Oversized Materials, 1876-1930; 1 box; 41 folders
  Oversized materials consists of oversize photographs, portraits, newspapers, paintings and etchings, scrapbooks and a tape recording and film strip.
  The oversize materials are arranged in no particular order.
  - Photographs Oversize: Photograph of Inaugural of President Wilson at Washington, D.C., 1913 March 4; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Oversize; 1 caricature, 1 collage ("Wilson – That's All" – from liquor advertisement), undated; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Oversize; Princeton Faculty with President Wilson, Woodrow, includes Marquand, Alan, 1903 2 images, 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of Wilson and unidentified group, [ML 1993-2], undated; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Class of 1879 14 images, 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - New York Times, New York World, Portraits of Wilson, 1 partial panorama of Paris Peace Conference (3 images), undated; 1 folder (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Appointment of Ezell, Lula, as postmaster of Timpson, Texas; DS, 1916 January 7; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder Item 1)
  - Proclamation, "Red Cross Week," 1918 May 20 DS, gift: Hyatt, Thaddeus P., 1918 May 7, 1 folder (Box 108, Folder Item 2)
  - The New York Times, 1914-1918 Gift of Lytle, Mr. Richard R., Class of 1876, 1 folder (Box 108, Folder Item 3)
  - Harper's Weekly, "The New President of Princeton,", 1902 June 21; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder Item 4)
  - Newspapers (Miscellaneous), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 108, Folder Item 5)
  - "A Tribute to Woodrow Wilson Democracy Embracing the World" (carbon gold painting), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 109, Folder Item 1)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, House, Wilson, Woodrow, Foundation, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder Item 1)
  - Oval Portrait of Wilson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 110, Folder Item 2)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Matter (2 items), undated; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder Item 1)
  - Framed Wilson Address from New York Times, 1917 April 3; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder Item 2)
  - Oil Painting, Levy, Estelle, "Garden in Old Lyme, Connecticut" (a favorite walk of Wilson), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 111, Folder Item 3)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, for Governor, Campaign Poster/Photograph, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 112, Folder Item 1)
  - Etchings/Lithograph of Wilson (3 items), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 112, Folder Item 2)
  - Miscellaneous Portraits, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 112, Folder Item 3)
  - Tape Recording, "Recollections of Woodrow Wilson by Howard L. Hughes" AM 19398, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 113, Folder Item 1)
  - Sound Filmstrip, "Woodrow Wilson: Idealism and American Democracy," AM 19449, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 113, Folder Item 2)
  - Record, Addresses on "Labor" and 'The Tariff" AM 18105, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 113, Folder Item 3)
  - Halleran, W. J., Scrapbook, Newspaper Articles, undated; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder Volume 1)
  - Halleran, W. J., Scrapbook, Newspaper Articles, 1929-1930; 1 folder (Box 115, Folder Volume 1)
  - Halleran, W. J., Scrapbook, Newspaper Articles, undated; 1 folder (Box 116, Folder Volume 1)
  - Photograph of Inaugural of President Wilson at Washington, D.C., 1913 March 4; 1 folder (Folder Oversize folder 1)